

Senior UX designer & UI developer

ABOUT ME

I am a passionate learner of new concepts, problem solver at heart and strive to deliver the most effective, cross-platform solutions at the highest of standards. Having multi skills experience always proved the quality output in prototyping, wire framing, team management & UI development.

SKILL SET

Programming

8	

	* * * \$ \$

	* * * \$ \$
	* * * \$ \$

Design Skill

Responsive web / mobile layout	****
Multimedia (Audio/video)	****
Graphics / Animation	***
Art & hand drawing	****

PROJECT WORK SKILL

Research & development	****
Interaction design	* * * \$
Team management	****

Imbuing empathy and perspective through 11+ years' experience in UX design, UI development.

https://pratapaditya.github.io№ New Delhi, IndiaPrataparya2012@gmail.com98683-75908 / 83688-51417

WORK EXPERIENCE

Secure meters Limited,

A utility based CMMI 3 Company

Senior UX design engineer (April 2020 to ...)

Lead to development team and work with RA-UX, UD and D&C team to deliver IA, wireframe, prototype as per the requirements and review of implementation at development floor.

UX design engineer (April 2018- March 2020)

Creating and monitoring attractive and functional products includes every aspect of usability in web creation, from coding to layout and visual design, functionality, and optimization.

Front end developer (April 2016- March 2018)

Development and research for the team with new front end technology for drag and drop tool for the live data dashboard.

Web designer (March 2011-March 2016)

As per the project requirements propose the layout and after approval of branding group create and code the web pages with graphics and animation.

User Experience Tool

User research	****	Photoshop CS6	****
Lo-fi/Hi-fi prot	.0★★★★☆	Adobe XD 44.0	****
Wire-framing	****	Just in mind8.0	****
Persona	* * * * *	VS code 1.8	* * * * *

COMPANY's APPRECIATION (Personal skill)

Learnability	****	Competency	****
Communicatio	n★★★☆☆	Adaptability	* * * \$ \$
Empathy	****	Self-motivatio	n★★★★☆

EDUCATION

MCA (Master of Computer Application)

NISCAIR, New Delhi / 2007 / 1st class

COP-U (Language proficiency)

JNU, New Delhi / 2007 / 1st class

BIT (Bachelor of Information Tech)

UICT, New Delhi / 2005 / 1st class

BTEC-HND (Computing & multimedia)

Edexcel (UK, London)/2004/1st class

QUALIFIED EXAM

GATE (CS-IT M. Tech)/2010/92.79 Percentile GATE (CS-IT M. Tech) 2009/87.28 Percentile JNU (CS-M Tech)/2008/50 AIR

HOBBY & INTEREST









Fun

Ι

Dynamic Work har

Work hard New idea









Drawing

Music

Puzzle solve Net surf

VENDOR CERTIFICATION





Mobile Experience: 2021

Usability Testing: 2021





Adv. professional: 2021

Design thinking: 2021

PERSONAL DOSSIER

Date of birth: 15/01/1983

Father's name: Prof. (Dr.) R. N. 'Arya"

Nationality: Indian

LANGUAGE

Hindi: Native English: Fluent

COMMERCIAL PROJECTS

Project type: Web application

Role: web designer and UI error solver

Technology: Asp.net, Html, CSS, JS, Jquery

■ ABT (Availability Based Tariff)

■ MDAS (Meter Data Acquisition System)

■ RAPDRP
■ Track-net

■ Gas-MBC ■ SAMAST DSM

Project type: Progressive web app

Role: Theme designer and developer

Technology: angular 8, Dojo, jsPlumb,D3 js

■ GIS (Geographical information System)

■ NGDCS-New Generation Smart Home

■ MIMIC-Canvas(Drag-Drop SCADA system)

Project type: *Hybrid android app*

Role: Full stack developer & designer

Technology: Cordova, php, BS4, Iquery

■ smartpanchayat ■ Stand-N-stride

■ Pratapaditya ■ Shubhashray

■ Agal bagal ■ Desi sawari ■ agalbagal

ACTIVITIES

Awards Seminars

Inter school Drawing Amity University

College scholarship Adobe

'E-Gyan kosh' award Microsoft

Top learner award Stand-n-stride

(Secure meters)

FOLLOW ME@SOCIAL MEDIA

https://pratapaditya.github.io

https://freeux24.wordpress.com/